<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>mikrotik - Label - Teknologi Untuk Hidup - by Larry Marzan Jr.</title><link>https://larrymarzanjr.github.io/tags/mikrotik/</link><description>mikrotik - Label - Teknologi Untuk Hidup - by Larry Marzan Jr.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>id</language><copyright>joenmarz</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 09:41:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://larrymarzanjr.github.io/tags/mikrotik/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>MikroTik Routerboard and HSGQ OLT Setup Notes</title><link>https://larrymarzanjr.github.io/mikrotik_and_hsgq_olt_setup_notes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 09:41:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Larry Marzan Jr.</author><guid>https://larrymarzanjr.github.io/mikrotik_and_hsgq_olt_setup_notes/</guid><description>MikroTik Routerboard and HSGQ OLT Setup Notes Mikrotik Side Setup DHCP Client ether1 Allow masquerade connection in Firewall menu Create VLAN : VLAN10-Hotspot, VLAN20-PPPoE, VLAN30-Console under the interface ether4-OLT Create bridge bridge-LAN for normal DHCP ports in this case ether2 and ether3 will be the slave ports, and bridge-hotspot for hotspot ports in this case VLAN10 will be the slave port. Setup IP Pool for bridge-LAN Setup IP Pool for bridge-hotspot Setup DHCP Server for bridge-LAN Setup Hotspot Server for bridge-hotspot OLT HSGQ Side: To setup HSGQ OLT for the first time, we power it on, then connect your Ethernet Cable from your Laptop Ethernet Port to the HSGQ OLT GE2 port (optionally can be plugged in to GE1,GE3,GE4 port).</description></item><item><title>Instalasi WinBox 4 Linux Native (Debian/Ubuntu)</title><link>https://larrymarzanjr.github.io/2025-08-27-install-winbox-4-in-debian/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 16:40:00 +0800</pubDate><author>Larry Marzan Jr.</author><guid>https://larrymarzanjr.github.io/2025-08-27-install-winbox-4-in-debian/</guid><description>Instalasi WinBox 4 di Linux Native (Debian/Ubuntu) 1. Download Winbox 4 for Linux Download dari situs resmi MikroTik:
1 wget https://download.mikrotik.com/routeros/winbox/4.0beta30/WinBox_Linux.zip 2. Extract File dan Buat Executable 1 2 3 unzip WinBox_Linux.zip -d WinBox_Linux cd WinBox_Linux chmod +x WinBox 3. Install pre-requisite paket 1 2 sudo apt update sudo apt install -y libxcb-icccm4 libxcb-image0 libxcb-keysyms1 libxcb-render-util0 libxcb-shape0 libxcb-xfixes0 libxcb-sync1 4. Jalankan WinBox 1 .</description></item></channel></rss>